My first special came out about a year
and a half ago and it did better than I
ever could
expected, but it was the first thing I
ever had out there that had enough
traction where people would actually
leave comments on my comedy. And I'm
stupid enough where I will read those
comments, but I'm also a comedian, so I
only notice the negative parts of it,
you know. And the guy that the one guy
that got me that bugged me, he just had
a forward comment after my four words
after the end of it. and he just
forwards and just said a fat Harry
Potter. Not exactly constructive
criticism is what I'm getting at. But I
was talking to my wife about this. She
said, "Why do why do you read that?
Why?" I said, "This guy called me a fat
Harry
Potter." I looked I was like, "Dan, do
do I look like Harry Potter?" She's
like, "Chad, you do not look like Harry
Potter." And I said, "Am I fat?" She
said, "Chad, you do not look like Harry
Potter." I understand sometimes people
just don't know what to say after a
show. I get it. I had a woman come up to
me after a show and she said, "I would
like to give you a compliment." I said,
"Okay, what's that?" She said, "I'm not
sure if you're funnier than the other
guy, but he's better
looking." I said, 'I'm not sure you know
what the word compliment
means, but I've been on stage on stage
about a minute now and I haven't been
physically escorted off stage, which
means by definition, this can't be the
worst show that I've ever
had. Now, because here's that
story. I was doing some stuff in Atlanta
and I was driving back to Missouri. Now,
if you know anything about geography, I
have to go across the very western part
of Tennessee. As I'm going through
there, a guy calls me. It's Comedy
Booker. He said, "Hey, I just checked
your schedule. Is there any chance
you're near such and such Tennessee?"
And I punched up like, "Yeah, I'm like
20 minutes from there." He said, "That's
amazing." He said, "I just had a guy
cancel a show on me." He said, "It
starts in about an hour." He said, "Why
don't you just go by and do the show?
Just tell them you're
him." Always a good
start. They're going to pay you in cash.
I'll even bonus you for bailing me out
and then you can go on home. So I get to
this gig and uh it was for the Tennessee
chapter of PETA, the people for ethical
treatment of animals. Now I have just
given you a piece of information that I
didn't
get. So I go up there, I tell my first
joke, haha, we're off and running right
now. The whole venue is kind of set up
like this. the stage is higher and it's
metal folding chairs and it's along the
rectangle in front row these chairs all
these women are holding small dogs like
what's the story with these dogs and
they said these are our therapy animals
and I said I've heard that phrase before
but what is exactly does that mean and
the guy in the back yells out he goes
those are animals that help keep us calm
and relaxed all right guy goes do you
have a therapy animal like well I guess
mine's a
cow he's like how is a cow a therapy
animal I said well it keeps me calm and
relaxed to know I have a freezer You're
full of
beef, physically escorted out the
door by two 80year-olds wearing matching
cat
[Laughter]
sweaters. But it is great to be here.
Um, and you will hear every comedian in
the world say, "It's great to be here.
It's great to be here." And what that
really means in the comedian world is
it's great to be getting paid. That's
what that
means. You know, I'm not trying to
destroy the illusion of comedy for
anybody, but if you know, if we were
doing this across the street in the
pharmacy, it'd be great to be there. I
mean, that's just kind of the way things
work. But I've got a little bit of a
different story for that now because I
work uh cruise ships every once in a
while. And uh I was supposed to take a
boat and my flight coming out of Dallas
Fort Worth got delayed and the boat left
without me. Now what the cruise lines do
when this happens, they fly you ahead to
the next port city. So that way when the
boat gets there, you're already there
and you just catch the boat and make up
any shows if you miss them. That's the
way they take care of those things. So
that's what it did. I was supposed to
catch a boat out of Cosml and they fly
me ahead and I stay at the hotel, start
to leave the next morning and the girl
said, "Uh, okay. The van's going to be
on your way to pick you up." I was like,
"Okay, that sounds good." I said, "How
far am I away from the boat?" And she
goes, "Ah, like four or five." I'm like,
"Oh, perfect." So, I'll be on the boat
in like 20 minutes. And she said, "No,
four or five
hours." Four or five hours. And then the
first part of the conversation replays
in my head, the van's going to pick you
up. I'm going to be in a
van going across
Mexico for four to five
hours. I've seen forensic files. I know
how some of these stories start off, you
know. So the van comes and picks me up
and we leave. Super nice guy, but he
looked at me. He said, do you talk the
Spanish?
No. He said, I don't talk the English.
And I said, I picked up on
that. He said, how about radio? And
there's one working speaker behind my
head. I'm like, okay, fine. Let's listen
to the radio. This guy loved Whitney
Houston, which was really weird to me,
you know, because we're driving 4 hours
across the back parts of Mexico, the
parts that you don't see on the travel
brochures. I mean, we're seeing the
abandoned cars and the burned out
buildings and everything's got graffiti
on. I'm kind of looking all this. It's
kind of sad. And the whole time I've
got, I want to dance with somebody. My
head was so weird,
right? So, we finally around the corner,
I can see the top of the boat. Like
finally, as we're going up there, the
Mexican police go and they form a single
file line across this road we're
supposed to go up. And I thought, "Oh,
well, this can't get any
worse." As I think that about 20 yards
behind them, the Mexican military line
up behind them. I mean, fatigues,
automatic weapons, the real thing. I was
like, "Oh, I stand corrected. This has
got much, much
worse." And the guy goes up there and he
rolls down the window. Now, I don't know
what they're saying because number one,
I don't talk the
Spanish. And number two, I can't hear
him anyway because I have I will always
love you blasting at 8,000 dB in my
head. So he goes up there, he makes this
little horseshoe turn. He turns around,
looks at me, and goes, "You must get
out." I said, "Well, how am I supposed
to get to the boat?" And he said,
"Walk." And I said, "Is everything
okay?" And he said,
"No." And I said, "You picked up on that
English pretty quick."
So I had to get out of the van and walk
the last quarter of a mile, dragging my
bags through gravel and dirt as the
Mexican military are on both sides of
me, finger on triggers, just waiting for
me to do something wrong so they can
open up fire on me. So when I tell you
tonight, Provo, that it is great to be
here. I mean, it is fantastic to be
here.